Md Mahin Arafat

Lippincott St, Toronto, ON M5T 2R5 | +16479977035 | mahinarafatmeem@gmail.com

Summary

Currently a post-graduate student of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Ontario Tech University with 2 years of experience in web development (including a year-long internship) with a strong understanding of software architecture, agile and scrum methodologies and a concrete understanding of Git and Bitbucket. Motivated to make computers even more amazing and looking for opportunities to grow.

Tools & Skills

Web development, Python, Django, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Git, BitBucket, JIRA, Bootstrap, Php, Agile Methodology, SUMO, Photoshop, Lightroom, FCPX, Software Architecture and Modelling, MS Office, Source Control.

Relevant Experience

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Strativ BD Limited | Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

- Worked on different web development projects.
- Learned to work on client-based projects, and attended and dealt with multiple clients.
- Utilized knowledge in SQL, Python, Django, and Javascript.
- Changed the entire theme and added functionalities for the internal ERP system.

WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER INTERN

Saleduck Asia | Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Worked with the development and maintenance of various websites of Saleduck.
- Worked in SASS, PHP, Laravel framework, HTML and CSS.
- Used professional product management tools and developer tools like Bitbucket, Slack, Git, Docker etc.
- Learned the basics of backend development and database such as MySQL.
- Followed and learned deeply and used the model, view and controller and used the components to maintain the system architecture.
- Successfully worked in frontend development.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SUMMER INTERN

Strativ BD Limited | Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Participated in changing website designs according to the clients' requirements.
- Learned how to make codes more effective and efficient using bootstrap tools.

Education

Masters of Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering | Ontario Tech University

Bachelor of CS in Computer Science(Software Engineering) | University of Malaya 2017 - 2021 | CGPA 3.24/4.0

Projects

Personal Portfolio Website (Gatsby, Javascript) - Ongoing

Vehicle Movement Detection based on Device Movement (Sumo, Python) - 2022

Fire Hazard Detection System (Fortran, Python) - 2022

Car Rental and Vehicle Breakdown assistant (Python, Django)- 2020

Personal Finance System Website (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React.js) -2018 Minimum Spanning Tree Finder (Python) - 2018

Smart English Tutor (Software Requirement Engineering) - 2018

Trello Landing Page (HTML, CSS, Jquery) - 2018

Traffic Light System (Machine Language) - 2017

Number Guessing Game A.I. (JAVA) - 2017

Bank Management System (JAVA) - 2017

Personal Blog (WordPress)- 2016

Extra Curricular Activities

Vice President

Dhaka College Photography Society | 2014 - 2015

- Managed to open a gallery for the enthusiasts.
- Planned and organized events every 2 months with guest photographers, which enabled me to learn how to organize events in a broader span.

General Secretary

Ideal School and College Debating Club | April 2011 - May 2012

- Nurtured the young minds of the school debaters.
- Was responsible for the team selection for competitions and club decisions.

Achievements & Certifications

- Danish Style Aquascape contest winner, 2015
- Various Inter-School Debate Competitions
- 1st Runner up, Adamjee Cantonment College Photography Festival, 2014
- IAPLC 2015 global rank winner
- Presentation Skill Specialization Course- University of Malaya